Finding Aid for Vulcans (University of Michigan) Records, 1904-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Vulcans (University of Michigan) records 1904-2009
Vulcans (University of Michigan)
1 oversize folders
2 linear feet
87350 Bimu F41 2
Senior engineering society at the University of Michigan. Minutes of meetings, constitution, membership lists, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the Vulcans, (donor # 3059 ) in 1954, 1976, 1979, 1987 and 1995.
The records are open to research.
The Vulcans, a senior engineering honorary society, was organized in 1904. In addition to social activities, the society raises money for scholarships for engineering students.
The Vulcans record group consists of minutes, financial records, and photographs relating to the activities of the Vulcan Honors Society. In addition to two boxes of manuscript material and photographs, the record group includes an oversized folder of composite and group photographs of Vulcans.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Honorary societies.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.; Vulcans (University of Michigan)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Carpenter shops.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1911-1920.; Vulcans (University of Michigan)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Records
  - Record Books
    - 1904-1926 (Box 1)
    - 1926-1958 (Box 1)
    - 1958-1974 (Box 1)
    - 1975-1979 (Box 1)
    - 1979-1984 (Box 1)
    - 1984-1990 (Box 1)
    - 1990-2000 (Box 1)
    - 2000-2004 (Box 1)
    - 2004-2007 (Box 1)
    - 2007-2009 (Box 1)
  - Text of an Unidentified Speech at a Vulcan meeting 1905 (Box 1)
  - Dues Book 1916-1926 (Box 1)
  - Open House/ Reunion Material 1941-1954 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Records 1949-1952 (Box 1)
  - Train Ticket Sales Activities 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Guest Register of 75th Reunion 1980 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  Photographs include images of freshman-sophomore rush, engineers' smokers and pow-wows, the engineering faculty, the wood shop, and composite portraits.
  - Engineer's "Smoker," 1912 (Box 2)
  - Engineer's "Smoker," 1913 (Box 2)
  - "Tug-of-War," 1913 (Box 2)
  - Freshman-Sophomore Rush 1913 (Box 2)
  - Engineer's "Pow-Wow," 1913 (Box 2)
  - Wood Shop 1913 (Box 2)
  - Engineers Rolling Large Ball Undated (Box 2)
  - Sophomore Engineering "Pow-Wow," 1914 (Box 2)
  - Sophomore Group Before "Tug-of-War," 1914 (Box 2)
  - Winners of the Freshman-Sophomore Contests 1914 (Box 2)
  - Freshman-Sophomore Rush Undated (Box 2)
  - Faculty of the Engineering Department Undated (Box 2)
  - Unbound Photographic Portraits, Classes of 1909, 1912 (Box 2)
  - Portrait of Charlie Kelley 1906 (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Official Composite Photographs and Description of their Present Locations (Box 2)
  - Folder of Vulcan Honoraries, Containing Photographs and Brief Interviews 1994 (Box 2)
  - Composite Portraits (Folder UBimul F41)
    - 1913 (Folder UBimul F41)
    - 1914 (Folder UBimul F41)
    - 1915 (Folder UBimul F41)
    - 1917 (Folder UBimul F41)
  - Group Photograph 1960-1961 (Folder UBimul F41)
  - Composite Portrait 1975 (Folder UBimul F41)
  - Group Photograph 1980 (Folder UBimul F41)
  - Unidentified Photo of Men Tussling, Perhaps in Initiation Activities (Folder UBimul F41)